Sytze Zeijlmaker

Full-stack Ruby on Rails Developer

sytzez@gmail.com github.com/sytzez linkedin.com/in/sytzez No sponsorship required

Personal statement

I'm a highly productive, solution-focused and collaborative software developer with 5+ years professional and 15+ years personal experience programming. I have a track record of unlocking stalled projects by providing teams with a technical vision, motiviation, the confidence to get started and the momentum to see things through. I care deeply about code quality and future-proofness, aiming for simplicity, readability, keeping related code close together, exhaustive testing of behaviour, and sensible performance trade-offs. I work with a broad perspective, keeping in mind product design, user experience, accessibility and business value and I love to contribute ideas beyond just the code.

Work experience

Senior Software Developer & Squad Lead Sumdog

Oct 2023 - Present

Ruby on Rails, Rspec, Scala (Akka), JavaScript (Vue.js), Postgres, AWS, Terraform, Gitlab

learn.sumdog.com

- Leading a team of senior developers, a QA and a PM, working across many technologies.
- Delivered the 'Fluency Booster' feature, which required substantive changes throughout the stack in complex and high throughput (~1.5M questions a day) areas. It enables more personalised, non-linear curriculum progression, reducing the average number of questions to complete a skill from 132 to 53, while improving insights in reports, increasing teacher engagement with the dashboard.
- Making improvements out of my own initiative. For example: I optimized an endpoint that took 20s for big schools to 7s. I optimized our most time consuming endpoint from 13% to 7% of total server time. I created several tools for QA and CS to save developer hours. I improved our CI pipeline to make it easier to deploy to various environments. I deleted 1000s of lines of unnessecary code. Pages had mixed Vue and AngularJS code competing for the History API; I separated that out to fix browser navigation functionality.

Head of Digital Development

University of Bath

Apr 2022 - Sep 2023

Ruby on Rails, JavaScript (jQuery), Oracle DBMS, Hugo (static site gen), Gitlab

bath.ac.uk

- Led team of 3 other developers and 1 UX designer, building features for bespoke CMS 'Typecase', acting as a lead developer, product manager and line manager, directly reporting to the CMO.
- Optimised time to publish a page from 2-3m to 30-50s, which includes regenerating the entire site.
- Led successful recruitment, interview process and onboarding for 2 new Ruby developers.

Full-stack Developer

Endeavour Group

Oct 2019 - Mar 2022

PHP (Laravel, Symfony, Codelgniter, Wordpress), TypeScript (Angular, Ionic), MySQL, Gitlab

endeavour.nl

- · Worked simultaneously for many clients such as Unit Victor, Okhuysen, Aalberts and BizzKiss, effortlessly switching between a large variety of tech stacks.
- Built full-stack features for web and mobile applications, autonomously and as part of small teams.
- Played a leading role launching greenfield front- and backend for dating app BizzKiss.
- Coached interns and trainees and held tech presentations.

Education

Muvis

Classical Composition

Codarts Convervatory

2014 - 2019

JavaScript, WebGL, GLSL, WebAudio, WebMIDI, SuperCollider

github.com/sytzez/audiovisual

Developed tools for real-time generated audiovisual performances and algorithmic music composition.

Personal projects

Muscade Service to render animations from MIDI. Rust (Axum, Bevy), Ffmpeg

2024

rpsbrawl.com Online multiplayer game.

Rust (Axum, Tokio), PIXI.is, Websockets Web app to render animations from MIDI and sync to audio. React/Redux, WebGL, GLSL

2024 2019

Games I've made countless small games. Flash, Blitz3D, C# (Unity), C (OpenGL) 2006-14

Read this CV in Ruby: github.com/sytzez/cv/blob/master/src/main.rb